我 被 卡 住 了 !
I'm stuck!
退回 去 !
Get back!
敦 蒂 先生
Mr. Tweedy.
那 只 雞 在 圍 欄 外 干 什 么 ?
What is that chicken doing outside the fence?
我 不知道 親愛 的
Oh! I don't know, love
馬上 去處 理 一下 !
Just deal with it. Now!
讓 我 難堪 我 要 教訓 你
I'll teach you to make a fool out of me
這 對 你們 都是 一個 教訓 !
Let that be a lesson to the lot of ya!
沒有 雞 能 從 敦 蒂 雞 場 逃出去 !
No chicken escapes from Tweedy's farm!
早 安 姜 妹 剛 度 完 假 ?
Morning, Ginger. Back from holiday?
我 沒去 度 假 巴 波斯
I wasn't on holiday, Babs.
我 被 關 禁閉 了
I was in solitary confinement
一個人 獨 呆 一陣子 也不 錯
Oh, it's nice to get a bit of time to yourself
是 不是 ?
isn't it?
集合 !
Roll call!
馬上 過來 你們 列隊 要 晚 了
Come along, now. You'll be late for parade
嘰 嘰 嘰 嘰 快點 兒 左 右 左 右
Pip, pip. Quick march. Left, right, left, right
左 右 左 右 !
Left, right, left, right!
快 精神 點 兒
Come on. Smarten up.
紀 律 ! 秩序 !
Discipline! Order!
想 當初 在 皇家 空 軍
Back in my R. A. F. days
當 長官 命令 緊急 起 飛
when the officer called for a scramble
你 跳進 老 飛 機 發現 目標
you'd hop in the old crate and tally- ho.
轟隆 開 走了 !
Chocks away!
別說 了 老 傻瓜
Give over, you old fool.
他們 只想 數數 我們
They just want to count us
你 怎 么 敢 這樣 對 長官 回 話 ?
How dare you talk back to a senior ranking officer?
嘿 想 當初 在 皇家 空 軍 ...
Why, back in my R. A. F. days!
福 羅 他們 來了
Fowler, they're coming
啊 好 好
Oh, right, right.
你 要 受到 嚴厲 的 譴責
There will be a stern reprimand for you, lad.
取消 你的 自由 活動
You're grounded
立 正 !
Attention!
歡迎 你 回來 母雞 有 新 的 計劃 嗎 ?
Welcome back, hen. Is there a new plan?
我 想 我們 試 過 從 下面 出去
I thought we tried going under
噢 上面 好
Ah! Over. Right
雞蛋 的 數量 怎 么 樣 ?
How's the egg count?
我 今 早 下了 五個 五個
I've laid five eggs this morning. Five!
那 很好 我 ... 很 高興
Well- chuffed with that, I was!
產 蛋 記錄
啊 不 愛 德 文 娜
Oh, no. Edwina
邦 迪 你 為 什 么 不 給 她 幾個 ?
Bunty, why didn't you give her some of yours?
我 會 的 可 她 沒說
I would have. She didn't tell me.
她 沒 對 任何人 說
She didn't tell anyone
噢 愛 德 文 娜 要 去 度 假 嗎 ?
Oh, is Edwina off on holiday?
我們 必須 逃離 此地
We've got to get out of here
姜 妹 ! 我們 還要 逃 嗎 ?
Ginger! Are we still on?
啊 當然 啦 我們 要 逃
Oh, we're on, all right
麥 克 告訴 大家 今晚 在 17 號 木 屋 開會
Spread the word, Mac. Meeting tonight in hut 17
你 叫 我們 ? 尼 克 ...
You called? Nick and...
- 范 晨 - 聽從 你的 吩咐
- Fetcher. - At your service
這 邊 兒 來
Over here
我們 還 需要 一些 東西
We need some more things
好 小 姐
Right you are, miss.
這 套 手工 茶 具 怎 么 樣 ?
How about this quality handcrafted tea set?
不要
Uh, no
那 來 條 漂亮 的 項鏈 和 掛 墜 ?
Or a lovely necklace and pendant?
是 不錯 ...
It's love...
或者 這個 美麗 的 帽 子
Or this beautiful number
都是 巴 黎 雞 圈 子 里 時 髦 的 東西
all the rage in the fashionable chicken coops of Paree
這樣 戴上
Simply pop it on like so
像 法 國 雞 那樣 說 聲 " 喔 哇 "
and as the French hens say, " Voila! "
那是 法 語
That's French
這 是個 兩 用 帽 小 姐
That's two hats in one, miss.
參加 晚 會 參加 婚禮
For parties, for weddings
啊 可是 女士 這 使 你 美 極 了
Oh, but madame, this makes you look like a vision
像 夢中 美人
like a dream
- 像 只 鴨 子 - 不要 謝謝
- Like a duck. - No, thank you
我們 在 做 這個 需要 這些
We're making this. We need THESE things.
你 能 搞 到 嗎 ?
Can you get them?
啊 啊 這 不容 易 小 姐
Oh, oh, oh, this is a big job, miss
啊 比 其 它 的 都 難
Oh, bigger than the others.
不 不 價錢 會 很 貴
No, no. This is gonna cost
價錢 不變 一袋 種子
Same as always. One bag of seed
- 這 是 你的 付 款 ? - 是 雞 飼料
- You call this pay? - It's chicken feed
- 我們 還能 給 你 什 么 ? - 雞蛋
- What else could we give you? - Eggs
- 雞蛋 ? - 雞蛋
- Eggs? - Eggs
我們 不能 給 你 雞蛋 太 珍貴 了
We can't give you eggs. They're too valuable
我們 也 珍貴
And so are we
你 先 請 范 晨
After you, Fetcher
我 先 請 什 么 ?
After I what?
走 !
Move!
二十 二 加 九
Twenty- two and nine
十四 先 令 加 三 便 士
Fourteen shillings and threepence
七 加 六 便 士 乘 三
Seven and sixpence times three
二 加 九
Two and nine
四個 半 便 士
Fourpence ha'penny
蠢 材 沒用 的 東西 !
D- oh! Stupid, worthless creatures!
我 做 夠 薄 利生 意 了
I'm sick and tired of making minuscule profits
厭倦 賺 小錢 的 生意 了
將你 的 雞 場 變成 金 礦
我 發財 了 !
啊 對
Oh, yes
這些 雞 有 什 么 詭計
Those chickens are up to something
安靜 我 找到 了 一個 方法
Quiet. I'm onto something
它們 組織 起來 了 我 知道
They're organized. I know it
- 我 說 安靜 - 那個 姜 妹
- I said, quiet. - That ginger one
我 認為 她是 頭 兒
I reckon she's their leader
敦 蒂 先生 !
Mr. Tweedy!
我 想 我 最終 找到 了
I may finally have found a way to
生 財 之道
make us some real money here
而 你 卻 在 干 什 么 ?
and what are you on about?
愚蠢 地 在 想 雞 會 逃跑
Ridiculous notions of escaping chickens
但是 ... 但是 ...
But... But...
都是 你 想 象 的 敦 蒂 先生 你 說
It's all in your head, Mr. Tweedy. Say it!
都是 我 想 象 的 都是 我 想 象 的
It's all in me head. It's all in me head
現在 你 自己 對 自己 重 復
Now, you keep telling yourself that
因為 我 再也 不想 聽到 它 了
because I don't want to hear another word about it
- 清楚 了 嗎 ? - 清楚 了 親愛 的
- Is that clear? - Yes, love
但 你 知道 那個 姜 妹 ...
But you know that ginger one...
它 只是 只 雞 傻瓜 !
It's chickens, you dolt!
除你 之外
Apart from you
它們 是 地球 上 最 蠢 的 動物
they're the most stupid creatures on this planet!
他們 不會 搞 陰謀 詭計
They don't plot, they don't scheme
他們 沒有 組織
and they are not organized
秩序 ! 秩序 !
Order! Order!
大家 安靜 安定
Quiet, everyone. Settle down.
我 請 你們 注意 秩序 ...
I would like to call to order! Please
如果 你們 能夠 ...
if you could just...
大家 有 點 兒 紀 律 ! 什 么 什 么 !
Let's have some discipline in the ranks! What, what!
- 謝謝 福 羅 - 當年 我 在 皇家 空 軍
- Thank you, Fowler. - In my R. A. F. day
我們 從不 允許
we were never allowed to waste time
閑 聊 浪費 時間
with unnecessary chit- chat
是 謝謝你 福 羅
Yes, thank you, Fowler
我 ...
I...
對 !
Right!
繼續 吧
Carry on
我 知道 上次 的 逃跑 行動
Now, I know our last escape attempt was
有 點 兒 失敗
a bit of a fiasco
但 麥 克 和 我 又有 了 新 計劃
but Mac and I have come up with a brand- new plan
- 給 他們 看看 麥 克 - 好
- Show 'em, Mac. - Right
我們 試 著 從 鐵 絲 網 下 出去 但 沒有 成功
We tried going under the wire and that didn't work
因此 這個 計劃 是 ... 從 上面 過
So, the plan is... we go OVER it
這 是 我們 明白 嗎 ?
This is us, right?
我們 這樣 進去
We get in like this
把 它 拉緊 ... 松 手 !
Wind her up and... let her go!
天 啊 這個 蘿 卜 完 蛋 了 !
Good grief! The turnip's bought it!
農夫 來了 !
Farmer's coming!
隱蔽 行動 !
Operation Cover- up!
敦 蒂 先生 !
Mr. Tweedy!
- 你 在 哪兒 ? - 都是 你 想 象 的
- Where are you? - Ooh. It's all in your head
都是 你 想 象 的 都是 你 想 象 的
It's all in your head. It's all in your head
各位 想想 我們 還有 什 么 沒有 試 過 ?
Think, everyone, think. What haven't we tried yet?
我們 還沒 試 過 不 逃跑
We haven't tried NOT trying to escape
嗯 那 可能 行 得 通
Hmm. That might work
記得 愛 德 文 娜 ?
What about Edwina?
還 得 有 多少 空 窩 才 行 ?
How many more empty nests will it take?
也許 如果 她 花 更多 的 時間 下蛋
Perhaps it wouldn't be empty
而不是 逃跑
if she'd spent more time laying
她 的 窩 就 不會 空
and less time escaping
所以 你 一生 都 在 下蛋 ...
So laying eggs all your life...
然 后 被 拔 毛 填 料 烘 烤
and then getting plucked, stuffed
這樣 夠 好了 吧 ?
and roasted is good enough?
這 是 命運
It's a living
你們 知道 問題 在 哪兒 嗎 ?
You know what the problem is?
圍 欄 不僅僅 將 農場 圍住
The fences aren't just round the farm.
也 將你 們 的 思想 圍住 了
They're up here in your heads
那 里 有 個 更好 的 地方
There's a better place out there
就 在 山丘 那邊 兒
somewhere beyond that hill
那 里 空間 開闊 樹木 眾多 ...
and it has wide open spaces and lots of trees...
還有 草原
and grass
你 能 想 象 出 嗎 ? 翠綠 的 草原
Can you imagine that? Cool, green grass
- 誰 來 喂 我們 ? - 我們 自 力 更 生
- Who feeds us? - We feed ourselves
- 那 農場 在 哪兒 ? - 沒有 農場
- Well, where's the farm? - There is no farm
那 農夫 住 在 哪兒
Then where does the farmer live?
沒有 農夫 巴 波斯
There is no farmer, Babs
- 他 去 度 假 了 嗎 ? - 他 哪兒 也沒 去
- Is he on holiday? - He isn't anywhere
你 還不 明白 嗎 ?
Don't you get it?
沒有 早 點名 沒有 農夫
There's no morning head count, no farmers
沒有 狗 雞 舍 和 鑰匙
no dogs, coops and keys
也沒有 圍 欄
and no fences
我 一生 中 從沒 有 聽過 如此 精 彩 的 ...
In all my life I've never heard such a fantastic...
一堆 廢話 !
load of tripe!
哎 面對 現實 吧 親愛 的
Oh, face the facts, ducks
從 這 兒出 去 的 機 率
The chances of us getting out of here
只有 百 萬分 之一
are a million to one
那 我們 仍有 機會
Then there's still a chance
啊 不 啊 不 我 在 干 什 么 ?
Oh, no, oh, no, oh, no. What am I doing?
你 想 騙 誰 ?
Who are you trying to fool?
你 不能 誘騙 這 群 ...
You can't lead this bunch of...
啊 老 天 幫幫 我們
Oh, heaven help us
自由 !
Freedoooom!
女士 們 先生 們 謝謝你 們
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen
你們 是 極 好 的 觀 眾
You've been a wonderful audience
噢 好 的
Oh, yes
有 辦法 了 !
That's it!
快 把 他 搬進 去
Get him inside quickly
這 是 我們 出去 的 辦法
THIS is our way out of here
我們 做 海 報 ?
We'll make posters?
不 是 海 報 上 的 畫 兒 巴 波斯
No. What's ON the poster, Babs. What's ON the poster
我們 將 飛 出去 !
We'll fly out!
有 他的 照片 一定 是個 人物
He must be important to have his picture taken.
他 是 干 什 么 的 ?
What does he do?
這 還不 明顯 嗎 ? 他 是 職業 飛行 公 雞
Isn't it obvious? He's a professional flying rooster
他 在 農場 間 做 示 范 飛行
He flies from farm to farm, giving demonstrations
- 你 這樣 認為 ? - 啊 當然
- Do you suppose? - Oh, absolutely
不能 在 暗處 不 不能 在 這 兒
Not in the dark, no. No, not in there. No
出去 好 要 拿 ...
Get out. Good. Gotta get...
你們 是 誰 ? 我 在 哪兒 ? 發生 了 什 么 事 ?
Who are you? Where am I? What's going on?
哎呀 ! 我 的 翅膀 怎 么 了 ?
Ouch! What happened to my wing?
你 剛才 跌 得很 慘
You took a rather nasty fall
你 扭傷 了 前 腱
And sprained the anterior tendon
我 給 你 捏 了 捏 包 扎 了 一下 兒
I gave it a wee bit of a tweak and wrapped her up
這 是 英 語 嗎 ?
Was that English?
你 扭傷 了 翅膀 她 弄 好了
You sprained a wing. She fixed it
- 是 我 做 的 繃帶 - 是 我 抱 你 進來 的
- I made the bandage. - I- I carried you in
我們 從頭 開始 說 我 在 哪兒 ?
Let's back up and start from the top. Where am I?
你 說得 對 真 沒 禮 貌 我們 只是 太 激動 了 ...
You're right. How rude. We're just very excit...
這 是個 養 雞 場
This is a chicken farm
我們 都是 雞
And we're the chickens
哦 現在 明白 了 雞 場 雞 ...
Yeah, with you so far. Chicken farm, chickens...
我 不喜歡 他的 樣子
I don't like the look of this one.
他 兩眼 的 距離 太近 了
His eyes are too close together
- 福 羅 別 這樣 - 他 還 是個 美國 佬 !
- Fowler, please. - And he's a Yank!
別 急 老大 爺 在 我們 那 兒 斗 雞 是 違法 的
Easy, Pops. Cockfighting's illegal where I come from
那 究竟是 什 么 地方 ? ?
And where is that exactly?
一個 我 稱之為 自由 之地
A place I call the land of the free
勇敢 之 家 的 地方
and the home of the brave
- 蘇 格 蘭 ! - 不 美國
- Scotland! - No! America
美國
Oh! America
胡 扯 愛 管 閑 事 的 美國 人
Poppycock. Pushy Americans.
每次 打仗 總是 晚 出 場
Showing up late for every war
掙 得 多 愛 得 多 來 這 兒 了 !
Overpaid, oversexed and over here!
老 爺 爺 怎 么 啦 ?
What's eating Grandpa?
哦 別 在 意 這 位 先生 ...
Oh, don't mind him, Mister! Mister?
我 叫 洛 基 · 羅德 紅 島 的 洛 基 簡 稱 羅德
Name's Rocky. Rocky the Rhode Island Red. Rhodes for short
- 洛 基 · 羅德 ? - 很 順 耳 是 吧 ?
- Rocky Rhodes? - Catchy, ain't it?
羅德 先生 這 是 你 嗎 ?
Um, Mr. Rhodes, is this you?
誰 想 知道 ?
Uh, who wants to know?
一 群 十分 絕望 的 雞
A group of rather desperate chickens
你 看 如果 是 你
You see, if it is you
那 你 可能 就是 我們 祈禱 的 答案
then you just might be the answer to our prayers
那 么 就 叫 我 奇 跡 吧 娃 娃 臉 因為 那 就是 我
Well, then, call me a miracle, dollface, 'cause that's me
你 怎 么 來 英 國 了 羅德 先生 ?
And what brings you to England, Mr. Rhodes?
那 當然是 因為 英 國 的 美 女 了
Why, all the beautiful English chicks, of course
別 逗 了 !
Give over!
你 看 我 天生 喜歡 旅行
You see, I'm a traveler by nature
我 在 農 舍 呆 過
I've done the whole barnyard thing
但 我 很不 適 應
but I couldn't get into it
嗨 你 好 ? 諾 鋪
Hi. How are you? Nope
自由 自 在 這 才是 我 的 方式
The open road. That's more my style
對 給 我 個 背 包
Yep, just give me a pack on my back
告訴 我 方向
and point me where the wind blows
實際上 你 知道 在 我 家鄉 他們 叫 我 什 么 嗎 ?
In fact, you know what they call me back home?
你們 會 喜歡 的 孤獨 的 自由 浪 人
You're gonna love this. The Lone Free Ranger
很 偉大 吧 ?
Isn't that great?
- 我 知道 有 可能 - 有 可能 對
- I knew it was possible. - Oh, it's possible, all right
- 我 知道 會有 辦法 的 - 阿們 !
- I knew the answer would come. - Amen!
我們 都 將 飛過 那個 圍 欄
We're all going to fly over that fence
羅德 先生 給 我們 示 范 對 吧 ?
and Mr. Rhodes is going to show us how, right?
那 ... 什 么 ? 你 說 " 飛 " ?
That's... What? Did you say " fly" ?
- 你 可以 教 我們 - 不 我 不能
- You can teach us. - No, I can't
聽 著 噓 你們 聽到 了 嗎 ?
Listen. Shh. You hear that?
那是 自由 大道 在 叫 我
That's the open road calling my name
我 生來 就 對 此 有 反應
and I was born to answer that call
他的 聽 力 一定 很好
He must have very good hearing
是 是 出口 在 哪兒 ? 啊 在 這 兒
Okay, okay, where's the exit? Ah, this way
羅德 先生 也許
Mr. Rhodes, um, perhaps
我 沒有 把 我們 的 處境 講 清楚
I didn't explain our situation properly
我們 一天 到 晚 下蛋
We lay eggs day in and day out
當 我們 再也 不能 下蛋 時 他們 就 殺了 我們
and when we can't lay any more, they kill us
這 是個 殘酷 的 世界 娃 娃 臉
It's a cruel world, doll face.
你 或許 應該 適 應 它
You might as well get used to it
" 他們 要 殺 我們 " 你 都 明白 了 嗎 ?
Which part of " they kill us" do you not understand?
我 也有 自己 煩惱 的 事
I got my own set of problems to worry about
此外 從 這個 鳥 籠 子 出去 也 并 不太 難
Besides, this birdcage can't be that hard to bust out of
實際上 瞧 著 我
In fact, watch me
一 只 甚至 兩 只 雞
It's not so hard to get one chicken
出去 并 不 難
out of here or even two
但 我們 全 要 出去
but this is about all of us
全部 出去 ?
All of you?
這 就是 我 一直 想 告訴 你的
That's what I've been trying to tell you
等等 讓 我 搞 清楚
Wait a minute. Let me get this straight
你 想 讓 所有 的 雞
You want to get every chicken
同時 從 這 兒 逃出 ?
in this place out of here at the SAME TIME?
- 當然 - 你 瘋了 !
- Of course. - You're certifiable!
你 不能 做 這 種 驚 險 的 事
You can't pull off a stunt like that.
這 是 自殺
That's suicide
有 志 者 事 竟 成
Where there's a will, there's a way
完全 同意 我 要 從 那 兒 走了
Couldn't agree more. I WILL be leaving that way
- 但 ... 請 別 走 ! - 我 就是 這 種 人 ...
- But... Please! - I'm the type of guy
我 喜歡 自由 我 從來 沒有 在 一個 地方 ...
That likes to roam around I'm never in one...
原來 如此 你 是 馬 戲 團 的
So that's it. You're from the circus
你 是 逃出來 的 是 不是 ?
You're on the run, aren't you?
你 能不能 小聲 點 兒 ?
You wanna keep it down?
我 正在 躲藏
I'm trying to lay low here.
我 應當 馬上 宣揚 出去
I should turn you in right now
你 不會 的 對 吧 ?
You wouldn't. Would you?
給 我 個 不會 的 理由
Give me one reason why I shouldn't
因為 我 很 ... 可愛 ?
Because I'm... cute?
嗨 嗨 ! 你 是 哪種 瘋 雞 ?
Hey, hey, hey! What kind of crazy chick are you?
你 知道 我 被 找到 下 場會 咋 樣 ?
Do you know what'll happen if he finds me?
這 是個 殘酷 的 世界
It's a cruel world
我 剛剛 決定 我 不喜歡 你
I just decided. I don't like you
我 剛剛 決定 我 不 在 乎
I just decided. I don't care.
現在 給 我們 示 范 飛行
Now, show us how to fly
- 用 這 只 翅膀 ? - 那 就 教 我們 吧
- With this wing? - Teach us, then
不 !
No!
他 很有 價值 你 剛才 說 ?
He's valuable, you say?
- 當然 - 拿 電 筒 來
- Sure. - Get the torch
現在 聽 著 姊妹
Now, you listen here, sister.
我 再也 不想 過 那 種 生活 了
I'm not going back to that life
我 是個 孤獨 的 自由 浪 人 喜歡 自由
I'm a Lone Free Ranger. Emphasis on FREE!
那 也是 我們 的 追求 自由 !
And that's what we want. Freedom!
喜歡 自由 他們 向 這 里 走來 了
Fancy that. They're coming this way
啊 不 他們 是 來 抓 我 的
Oh, oh, no. No. They're on to me
教 我們 飛行 我們 就 把 你 藏起來
Teach us to fly and we'll hide you
如果 我 不 呢 ?
And if I don't?
你 爸爸 也是 這 么 卑鄙 嗎 ?
Was your father by any chance a vulture?
我們 成 交了 嗎 ?
Do we have a deal?
是 實行 交易 的 時候 了 娃 娃 ...
Time to make good on that deal, doll...
我 叫 姜 妹
The name is Ginger
- 舒服 嗎 ? - 不太 舒服
- Comfortable? - Not really
這 也許會 有 所 幫助
Maybe this will help
藏 窩 不錯
Nice hideout
哎 喲 比 蛋 殼 還 小
Ouch. I had more room in my egg
我們 履行 了 我們 的 諾言
We've held up our end of the deal.
明天 你 得 履行 你的 了
Tomorrow you hold up yours
- 什 么 諾言 ? - 飛行 !
- What deal? - The flying!
噢 對 對 別 擔心
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Right, right, right. Don't worry
我 將 傾 囊 相 授
I'll teach you everything I know
現在 我 的 床 在 哪兒 ?
Now, which bunk is mine?
真是 太 氣 人 了 !
Absolutely outrageous!
讓 一個 長官 和 別人 睡 一張 床 ...
Asking a senior officer to share his quarters...
和 一個 美國 小 兵 太過 分 了
and with a noncommissioned Yank, no less
想 當初 我 從 ...
Why, back in my day, I'd never!
你 也不 是 我 的 首 選
You weren't exactly my first choice, either
挪開 點 兒 你的 翅膀 到 我 這 邊 兒 了
And scoot over. Your wing's on my side of the bunk
你 那邊 兒 ?
Your side of the bunk?
整 張床 都是 我 的
The WHOLE bunk is my side of the bunk!
等等 ... 什 么 味道 ? 是 你的 口 臭 ?
Just... What's that smell? Is that your breath?
真是 太 氣 人 了 !
It's absolutely outrageous
因此 你們 想 飛行 嗯 ?
So you wanna fly, huh?
好 這 并 不容 易
Well, it ain't gonna be easy
一 朝 一 夕 是 學 不會 的
and it ain't gonna happen overnight
你 知道 飛行 得 有 三樣 東西
You see, flying takes three things
努力 練 習 不 屈 不 撓 ...
Hard work, perseverance and...
- 努力 練 習 - 你 說 兩次 努力 練 習 了 !
- Hard work. - You said hard work twice!
那是 因為
That's because
它 比 不 屈 不 撓 難 兩倍
it takes twice as much work as perseverance
一派胡言 !
Codswallop!
現在 最 重要 的 是
Now, the most important thing is
我們 要 共同 合作
we have to work as a team
這 意味 著 ... 我 說什 么 你們 就 做什 么
which means... you do everything I tell you
好 ! 我們 開始 吧 !
Right! Let's rock and roll!
敦 蒂 先生 ! 雞 都 在 ...
Mrs. Tweedy! The chickens are...
吃食 ?
Pecking?
左 二 三 右 二 三
And left, two, three. And right, two, three
嗯 ... 停下 啊 對 往 下
And... stop right there. Oh, yeah, down
往 下 對 轉 小 圈 就 這樣 快點 兒
Down. Yeah, make little circles. That's it. Faster
快點 兒 對 好極了
Faster. Oh, yes. Perfect
噢 就是 這 兒
Oh, that's the spot.
我 以為 你 要 教 我們 飛 呢
I thought you were going to teach us how to fly
我 正在 教 啊
That's what I'm doing
不是 該 有 些 拍 翅膀 的 動 作 嗎 ?
Isn't there usually some flapping involved?
嘿 我 告訴 你 怎 么 下蛋 了 嗎 ?
Hey, do I tell YOU how to lay eggs?
放心 我們 正在 進步
Relax. We're making progress
真的 ? 我 總 覺得 我們 在 兜 圈 子
Really? I can't help feeling we're going around in circles
這 ... 嘿 ! 停下 ! 你們 讓 我 頭 暈
What the... Hey! Cut it out! You're making me dizzy
我 想 他們 準備 好 飛行 了
I think they're ready to fly now
好 因為 他們 再也 走 不動 了
Good, because they certainly can't walk anymore
過來 姑娘 我們 拍 翅膀
Up and at 'em, gals. Let's flap
瞧 范 晨
Watch, Fetcher
我們 看看 老 母雞 是否 改變 了 主意
Let's see if old Attila the Hen has come to her senses
下 起 雞 雨 了 !
It's raining hen!
- 這 是 什 么 把 戲 親愛 的 ? - 我們 在 飛
- What's this caper, love? - We're flying
當然
Obviously
拍 翅膀 看 這 兒 范 晨
Flipping hell. Look at this, Fetch
他們 找 死 啊
They're gonna kill themselves
- 想看 下去 ? - 想 看 吧
- Wanna watch? - Yeah, all right
嗨 ! 小心 那些 雞蛋 !
Hey! Careful of those eggs!
單 煎 一面
Sunny- side up.
現在 他們 很 容易 翻過 來 !
Now they're over easy!
無疑 成了 炒 蛋
Definitely scrambled
走 ! 走 ! 走 !
Go! Go! Go!
走 走 走 !
Go, go, go, go! Go!
雞 在 行動 !
Poultry in motion!
物 以 類 聚 人以 群 分
Birds of a feather flop together
干 得 好 女士 們 干 得 好 !
Great work, ladies. Great work!
受 點 兒 苦 對 你們 不錯 是好 事
The pain you're feeling is a good thing. It's good
痛苦 是 你們 的 朋友 對 吧 ? 這 是好 事
Pain is your friend, okay? It's a positive thing
堅定 信念 ... 你 叫什 么 名字 ?
Just keep the faith, uh... What's your name?
安 吉 絲 ! 你 會 成功 的
Agnes! You'll get there
小 鴨 我 想你 今天 飛過 四 英 尺 了 !
Ducky, I think you flew four feet today!
對 四 英 尺 ! 從 屋頂 到 地面
Right, four feet! From the roof to the ground
女士 們 別 擔心
It's all part of the process, ladies.
這 是 成功 的 必 由 之路
Nothing to worry about!
你 這個 吃奶 酪 的 小 ...
Ya cheese- eating little...
這 聽起來 不太 好
That doesn't sound good. Ha, ha, ha
聽 大地 在 震動 我們 需要 擔心 嗎 ?
Okay, the ground's shaking. Are we worried?
我們 需要 擔心 嗎 ?
Are we worried?
馬 戲 團 快 把 我 藏起來
The circus. Quick. Hide me
- 藏起來 - 來
- Hide me. - Come on
像 瘋 雞 一樣 亂 拍 翅膀
One isn't awarded a medal
是 得 不 到 獎 章 的
like this for flapping about like a lunatic
你 看 這 兒 這 是 長官 的 地方
Now, see here! This is an officer's quarters
快 到 這 兒 來
Quick. In here.
馬上 出去 先生 !
Get out of here immediately, sir!
夠了 老 爺 爺
Give it a rest, Pops
出去 ! 本 周 我 不會 饒 了 你
Out of here! I shall have you on a charge within the week
家禽 產 品 有 限 公 司
謝謝 伙 計
Cheers, mate
都是 你 想 象 的 都是 你 想 象 的
It's all in your head. It's all in your head
都是 你 想 象 的
It's all in your head
什 么 ... 什 么 ... 這些 是 什 么 ?
What... What... What's all this, then?
這 是 我們 的 未來 敦 蒂 先生
This is our future, Mr. Tweedy
再也 不用 浪費 時間
No more wasting time with petty
收集 雞蛋 和 算 小 賬 了
egg collection and minuscule profits
不 收集 蛋 了 ? 可 我們 一直是 雞 農
No more eggs? But we've always been egg farmers
我 父親 的 父親 的 父親
Me father and his father and all their fathers.
他們 都是 ...
They was always...
窮 光 蛋 ! 一 文 不值
Poor! Worthless. Nothings
但 這 一切 都要 改變 了
But all that's about to change
這 將使 敦 蒂 雞 場 走出 黑暗 的 年代 ...
This will take Tweedy's farm out of the dark ages...
進入 大規模 的 自動 化 生產
and into full- scale automated production
我 再也 不是 窮 光 蛋 了
Melisha Tweedy will be poor no longer
操作 指 南
那 我 把 它 安裝 起來 好嗎 ?
I'll put it together, then, shall I?
這 不太 妙 麥 克
This isn't good, Mac
盒 子 里 的 東西 是 給 我們 的
Whatever's in those boxes is for us
我 想 不是 軟 草
and I don't think it's softer hay
啊 母雞 我 討厭 說 喪 氣 話
Aye, hen. And I hate to be the voice of doom
但 我 一直 在 思考
but I've been calculating
我們 生來 就 不適合 飛行
and I just don't think we're built for flying
但 我 看到 他 飛過 鐵 絲 網
But I saw him. He flew in over that fence
啊 啊 我 相信 你
Aye, aye, I believe you
但 如果 我們 能 親眼 看看
but if we could just see it for ourselves
那 就 能說 明 問題 了
that may answer some questions
你 說得 對 對不起
You're right. I'm sorry
我們 練 了 一個 周 可 一點 兒進 展 都 沒有
We've been at this all week, and we're getting nowhere
如果 他的 翅膀 好 點 兒 他 就 ...
If his wing were better, he could!
啊 ! 我 去 跟 他 說說
Oh! I'll have a word with him
他 在 哪兒 ?
Where is he?
他們 給 我 獎 章 不是 因為 我 是 美國 保姆
They didn't give me this medal for being a Yank nanny
一句 簡單 的 " 我 不知道 " 就 足夠 了
A simple " I don't know" would suffice
當心 那位 小 姜 妹
Beware of that one, young Ginger
那個 美國 佬 不可 信任
That Yank is not to be trusted
他 是 我們 離開 這 兒 的 希望
That YANK is our ticket out of here
豬 對馬 說
And the pig says to the horse
" 嗨 伙 計 為 什 么 臉 拉 這 么 長 ? "
" Hey, fella, why the long face? "
噢 瞧 瞧
Oh, oh, look, look
啊 雞 尾 酒 !
Oh. Cocktail!
別 逗 了 !
Give over!
好吧 ... 無論如何 ...
So, um, anyway...
明天 要 記住 飛行 事項
Remember those flying tips tomorrow.
這 很 重要
They're very important
一直 保持 想 飛 的 念頭
Keep thinking those flighty thoughts
噢 好
Oh, yeah
他們 是 一流 的 雞 真的 是
They're swell chicks. They really are
瞧 巴 波斯 給 我 織 了 什 么
Look at what Babs made me
一個 口 罩 很 可愛 吧 ?
A beak warmer. Isn't that the cutest?
那個 邦 迪 她 真有 勁
And that Bunty. She really packs a punch
有 什 么 問題 嗎 ?
Is there a problem here?
- 我們 飛過 圍 欄 了 嗎 ? - 還沒有
- Have we flown over that fence? - Not quite
那 就 有 問題 了
Then there's a problem
耐心 等待 才能 成功 娃 娃 臉
Good things come to those who wait, dollface
姜 妹 !
Ginger!
- 好 你 花了 多 長時間 ? - 做什 么 ?
- Okay, how long did it take you? - To do what?
學習 飛行 啊
To learn how to fly
蘋果 和 橘 子 洋 娃 娃
Apples and oranges, baby doll.
我 有 天賦 他們 卻 沒有
I'm gifted. They're not
兩者 不能 比較 對 吧 ?
You can't compare the two, okay?
問題 是 這些 事情 要 花 時間
The point is, these things take time
而 我們 很快 就 沒有 時間 了
Which we are rapidly running out of
我們 甚至 還沒 離開 地面
We haven't even lifted off the ground. Why?
信心 我 反復 想過
Trust. I went over my calculations
我 認為 關鍵 的 因 素 是 信心
and I figured the key element was trust
我 一點 兒 也不 明白
I- I didn't get a word of that
當 鴨 子 和 鵝 飛行 時
When birds like ducks and geese take off
他們 有 什 么 呢 ? 信心 !
what do they have? Trust!
我 發誓 她 用 錯了 詞
I swear she ain't using real words
- 她 說 我們 需要 更多 的 動 力 - 哦 動 力
- She said we need more thrust. - Oh, thrust
當然 我們 需要 動 力
Well, of course, we need thrust.
動 力 和 飛行 像 ... 這個 !
Thrust and flying are like... this!
- 希望 你 不 介意 ? - 當然
- Would you excuse us? - Aye
啊 翅膀 翅膀 翅膀
Ah, the wing, the wing, the wing
如果 明天 我們 還 看 不 到 結果 交易 就 取消 了
If we don't see some results by tomorrow, the deal is off
沒有 掩 護 了 他們 會 找到 你
No more hiding. They will find you
你 回 馬 戲 團 去 吧 飛 人 !
and it's back to the circus, flyboy!
我 從沒 遇到 像 你 這樣 難 交 的 雞
You're the first chick I ever met with the shell still on
睡 個 好 覺 天使 臉
Sleep tight, angel face. The Rock's on the case
喔 ... 喔 ! 什 么 什 么
Cock- a- doodle- doo! What, what
啊 很 漂亮 朋友
Oh, it was a beaut, guv'nor
如果 讓 我 說 一件 藝 術 精 品
A fine piece of work, if I do say so meself
- 我 也對 自己 說 - 希望 我 也 見過
- I say so meself, too. - Wish I could have seen it
我們 溜進 了 農夫 的 家里 悄悄地
We slipped into the farmer's room, all quiet like
- 像 條魚 - 對 我們 ...
- Like a fish. - Yeah, and we...
" 像 條魚 " ? 你 這個 笨 蛋
" Like a fish" ? You stupid Norbert
不管 咋 樣 這 給 你 朋友
Anyway, guv, here it is
- 你 要 的 貨 - 這 是 西班牙 語
- El merchandiso. - That's Spanish
這 倆 個 無賴 在 這 兒 干 什 么 ?
What are these two crooks doing here?
- 那 你們 認識 ? - 她 認為 我們 沒用
- So, you know each other? - She don't think we're valuable
伙 計 毫無疑問 你們 是 最 鬼鬼祟祟 的
Guys, you are without a doubt the sneakiest
我 所見 過 的 最 靈巧 的 竊賊
most light- fingered thieving parasites I've ever met
- 啊 別 別說 了 - 我 的 臉 都 紅
- Oh, don't, don't. Stop it. - I've gone bright red
那 ... 那些 雞蛋 呢 ?
So, uh, how about them eggs?
雞蛋 別 告訴 我 你 答應 他們 ...
Eggs? Don't tell me you promised them...
對 ! 答應 給 他們 這個 月 我 生 的 所有 的 蛋
Yep! Promised them every egg I lay this month
我們 什 么 時候 可以 拿到 第一 個 蛋 呢 ?
And when can we expect the first installment?
我 正在 準備 呢 我 會 通知 你的
I'm brewing one up as we speak. I'll keep you posted
很 高興 與 你 做生意 先生
Pleasure doing business with you, sir
傻瓜
Sucker
- 什 么 ? - 你 對 他們 撒謊
- What? - You've lied to them
我 沒有 娃 娃 臉 我 只是 隱瞞 了 一些 事實
I didn't lie, dollface. I just... omitted certain truths
我 會 履行 諾言 的
I'll give them exactly what I promised
那 就是 什 么 都 沒有
Which is nothing.
那 就是 我 要 給 他們 的
Which is what I'll give them
你 會 給 我們 什 么 ?
And what will you give us?
動 力 !
Thrrrust!
你 沒事 兒 吧 寶貝 兒 ? 好
You okay, sweetheart? Good, good
這 會對 你 有 點 兒 幫助
Now this is just a little helper
幫助 你 飛行 的 東西 動 力 訓練
Something to get you going. It's a thrust exercise
- 我 緊 張 死了 - 這 會 害死 她 !
- The tension's killing me. - It's gonna kill her!
松 手 !
- Release! - Whoa!
快 拍 翅膀 !
Come on! Flap!
你 能行 拍 拍 拍 !
You can do it. Flap, flap, flap!
對 對 對 !
Yes, yes, yes!
這 是 你 第一次 碰 壁 嗎 ?
Is that your first offense?
點名 了 ! 我 還沒 下蛋 呢
Roll call! I haven't laid any eggs
- 藏 起 我 - 三天 沒 下 一個 蛋
- Hide me. - Three days and not one
- 啊 不 ! - 為 啥 不 告訴 我們 巴 波斯 ?
- Oh, no! - Why didn't you tell us, Babs?
- 把 我 藏起來 ! - 我們 一直 忙 著 飛行 ...
- Hide me! - We've been busy with the flying...
- 他們 來了 ! - 快 藏 起 我 !
- They're coming! - Hide me!
自己 藏 吧 !
Hide yourself!
給 他們 雙倍 飼料 敦 蒂 先生
Double their food rations, Mr. Tweedy
我 要 他們 都 像這 只 這 么 肥
I want them all as fat as this one
我 的 一生 都 在 我 眼前 閃過 !
All of me life flashed before me eyes!
無聊 的 一生
It was really boring
雞 飼料 我 最 喜歡 的 !
Chicken feed. My favorite!
等等 !
Wait. Wait
不 等等 !
No. Wait!
巴 波斯 邦 迪 ! 停下 ! 等等 !
Babs, please! Bunty! Stop it! Wait!
停下 !
Stop!
Stop it!
有 點 兒 不 大 對 勁 兒 你們 看不出來 ?
Something is wrong here. Can't you see that?
倉庫 里 來了 許多 奇怪 的 盒 子 巴 波斯 不下 蛋 了
Strange boxes arrive in the barn. Babs stops laying
可 她 并 沒被 抓去 宰 了
but she's not taken to the chop
他們 還 給 我們 加 飼料
and now they're giving us extra food
你們 不明 白 發生 了 什 么 事 ? 他們 在 養肥 我們
Don't you see what's happening? They're fattening us up
他們 要 把 我們 全部 殺掉
They're going to kill us all
哇 哇 嚴重 警告
Whoa, whoa! Heavy alert.
她不 是 那個 意思 姑娘 們
She didn't mean that, gals.
你 不 介意 吧 ?
Do you mind?
接 著 吃 給 我 留 點 兒
Keep eating. Save some for me
你 在 干 什 么 ? 你 怎 么 敢 ... 放開 我 !
What are you doing? How dare you! Let go of me!
聽 著 我 遇到 了 不少 難 煮 的 蛋
Listen! I've met some hard- boiled eggs in my day
但 我 說你 得 煮 大約 20 分 鐘 !
but I'd say you're about 20 minutes!
你 這 是 什 么 意思 ?
What's that supposed to mean?
我 說你 該 輕 松 點 兒
It means you got to lighten up
在 美國 我們 的 規矩 是
Over in America, we have this rule
如果 你 要 激勵 某人 不要 提到 死
If you want to motivate someone, don't mention death
有 趣 這 里 的 規矩 是 :永遠 要 講 實話
Funny. Over here, the rule is:Always tell the truth
這 一直 很有 效 不是 嗎 ?
That's been working like a real charm, hasn't it?
這 里 有 些 免費 的 建議 你 要 試試 嗎 ?
Here's some free advice. You want them to perform?
- 說 他們 想 聽 的話 - 你 是 說 要 撒謊
- Tell them what they want to hear. - You mean lie
我們 又 轉 回來 了 你 知道 你的 問題 在 哪兒 嗎 ?
Here we go again. You know what your problem is?
你 ... 難 處
You're... difficult
為 什 么 ? 因為 我 誠實 ?
Why? Because I'm honest?
我 關心 他們 的 命運
I care about what happens to them
我 不期 待
something I wouldn't expect
孤獨 的 自由 浪 人 會 理解
a Lone Free Ranger to know anything about
如果 你 這樣 說
If this is the way you show it
我 希望 你 永遠 別 關心 我 !
I hope you never care about me!
- 我 可以 保證 不再 會 了 - 好 !
- I can assure you, I never will. - Good!
好 !
Fine!
發生 了 什 么 事 ?
What's all this?
哦 她 在 這 兒 問 她 就 知道了
Well, here she is. Ask and you shall receive
言 之 有 理
That's biblical
這 是 真正 的 手工 藝 品 真正 的
That's real craftsmanship, is what it is.
像 巖 石 一樣 硬
Solid as a rock
應該是 這樣
It's supposed to do that
- 太 完美 了 伙 計 - 蛋 怎 么 樣 了 ?
- It's perfect, guys. - And how's that egg coming?
是個 雙 黃 蛋
This is a double yolker
我 看不出 這 與 那 有 ...
I don't see what this has to do with...
你 會 的
You will
我們 一直 太 辛苦 了
We've been working too hard
應該 放 松 一下 兒 抖 抖 羽毛
Time to kick back a bit, shake those tail feathers
瞧 他 扭 來 扭 去 像 個 ...
Look at him. Nellypodging around like a...
啊 天 啊 發生 了 什 么 事 ?
Oh, good heavens. What's happening?
這 叫 音 節 姊妹
That's called a beat, sister.
感到 全身 沖 動 !
Feel it pulsing through your body!
啊 對 沖 動 喜歡
Oh, yes. Pulsing. Fancy that
嗨 好 我們 來吧 寶貝 兒
Hey, well, then go with it, baby
啊 天 啊 瞧 ! 我 會 跳了 !
Oh, my. Look! I'm going with it!
邦 迪 你 有 什 么 感覺 ?
Bunty, what's got into you?
很 明顯 跟 你的 一樣
Same thing that's got into you apparently
Flip flop fly I don't care if I die
就 跟著 樂 曲 走 姑娘 !
Just go with the flow, gal!
Flip flop fly I don't care if I die
Don't ever leave me don't ever say good- bye
現在 看著 我 我 不 記得 批 準 過 跳舞
Now, see here. I don't recall authorizing a hop
啊 閉嘴 跳 吧
Oh, shut up and dance
你 哭 什 么 南 希 ?
What are you sobbing about, you nancy?
此 情 此 景 伙 伴
Little moments like this, mate
這 使 工作 充滿 意義
It's what makes the job all worthwhile
想 跳舞 嗎 ?
Wanna dance?
對 想 跳
Yeah, all right
Now give me one more kiss hold it a long long time
Give me one more kiss hold it a long long time
Love me baby till the feeling hits my head like wine
So fine so glad that you're mine
Flip flop fly I don't care if I die
Don't ever leave me don't ever say good- bye
Yeah don't ever leave me don't ever say good- bye yeah
你 看到 我 飛 了 嗎 ?
Did ya see that? I flew!
干 得 好 姑娘
Attagirl, Babsy. Attagirl
- 你的 翅膀 好 點 兒 了 - 哦 ...
- Oh! Your wing. It's better. - Well...
- 怎 么 樣 ? - 太好了
- How about that? - Fantastic
你 明天 可以為 我們 飛行 了
You can fly for us tomorrow
嗯 ... 看起來 可以
Uh, uh, yeah, so it seems
我 飛 起來 了 ! 飛 起來 了 !
I flew! I flew!
看起來 我 應 向 你 道歉
Looks like I owe you an apology
我 以為 你 不關 心 我們
I didn't think you cared about us
但 經過 這 一切 ...
but after all this...
嗯 是 我 錯了
Well, it seems I was wrong
嗨 放 松 小 姐 倔 家 伙
Hey, easy, Miss. Hard- boiled
我 還 以為 你 變 溫柔 了
I might think you're turning soft
聽 著 有 件事 我 必須 告訴 你 ...
Uh, listen, there's something I got to tell ya. I...
不 你 最好 在 這 兒 等 著
No. You'd better wait here
這 真 棒 這 是 這 是 什 么 ?
Ooh, that's champion, that is. What is it?
是 餡 餅 機器 白 癡
It's a pie machine, you idiot
雞 進去 餡 餅 出來
Chickens go in, pies come out
什 么 餡 餅 ?
Ooh! What kind of pies?
- 蘋果 - 我 最 喜歡 的 !
- Apple. - My favorite!
雞 肉 餡 餅 大 笨 蛋 ! 想想
Chicken pies, you great lummox! Imagine it
不用 兩 個 周
In less than a fortnight
這 里 每家 商 店 ...
every grocers'in the county...
都 會 垛 滿 一 箱 箱 ...
will be stocked with box upon box...
敦 蒂 太太 家 制 雞 肉 餡 餅
of Mrs. Tweedy's Homemade Chicken Pies
敦 蒂 太太 的 ?
Just Missus?
女人 的 手藝 會 讓 大 眾 更加 滿意
Woman's touch. Makes the public feel more comfortable
啊 對 這 怎 么 操作 ?
Oh, right. How does it work?
找 只 雞 我 操作 給 你 看
Get me a chicken and I'll show you
我 知道 一 只 合適 的
I know just the one
我 有 個 賬 要 和 你 結 了
I've got a score to settle with you
我 的 天 啊 他們 抓走 了 姜 妹 !
Blooming heck! They've got Ginger!
我們 一定 不要 慌 不要 慌 !
We mustn't panic. We mustn't panic!
那邊 靜 點 兒
Quiet there!
我 說 靜 點 兒 ! 我們 要 有 紀 律
Quiet, I say! Let's have some discipline. What, what
敵人 抓 了 個 俘虜
The enemy has taken a prisoner.
我們 應該 報復 了
This calls for retaliation
報復 !
Retaliation!
怎 么 啦 ? 出了 什 么 事 ?
What's going on? What's happening?
他們 抓走 了 姜 妹 羅德 先生
They got Ginger, Mr. Rhodes.
他們 要 宰 了 她
They're taking her to the chops
那 你們 還 在 等 什 么 小子 們 ?
Well, what are you waiting for, laddie?
飛過 去救 她 !
Fly over there. Save her!
當然 ... 不 不 !
Of course... No, no! No
這 正是 他們 所 期望 的
that's just what they'd expect
但 我 說 我們 意外 出擊
But I say we give them the old element of surprise
打 他們 個 措手不及
And catch Jerry with his trousers down
聽起來 不錯 具 體 計劃 呢 ?
I like the sound of that. What's the plan?
計劃 ... 計劃
The plan... The plan
計劃 ... 巴 波斯 !
The plan... Uh, Babs!
給 我 那個 邦 迪 推 我 一把
Give me that thing. Bunty, give me a boost
瞧 那 機器 的 尺寸
Look at the size of that thing
不 !
Oh, no!
雞 進去
Chickens go in
餡 餅 出來
pies come out
雞 肉 餡 餅
Chicken pies
不是 ... 蘋果 餡 餅 是 雞 肉 的
Not... Not apple pies. Chicken
啊 好 好極了
Oh, great. Brilliant!
- 你 洋 娃 娃 ! - 羅德 !
- Yo, baby doll! - Rocky!
- 我 來了 ! - 快 !
- I'm coming! - Hurry!
- 我 就 要 來了 ! - 快點 兒 !
- I'm still coming! - Come on!
- 把 它 停下 ! - 我 正在 努力 !
- Stop this thing! - I'm getting there!
啊 媽 的
Oh, shoot!
洛 基 !
Rocky!
蔬菜 飼料
在 你 說什 么 之前 我 就 ...
I'll be down before you can say!
混合 蔬菜 !
mixed vegetables!
蔬菜
肉
面 團 !
D- oh! Get it? Dough!
- 我 粘住 了 ! - 沒 什 么 喔
- I'm stuck! - Nothing to it. Oops
把 住
Hang on!
小心 !
Look out!
調味 汁
好 !
Yes!
啊 這 里 像 個 烤 箱
Oh, it's like an oven in here
快 !
Come on!
等等 我 來了 ...
Wait up! I'm com...
別 丟下 ...
Don't leave...
到 那 ...
Get over to the...
門 ! 快 !
The door! Come on!
機器 要 爆 炸 了 快跑 !
She's gonna blow! Run!
系 統 故 障
調味 汁 壓力
你 做了 什 么 大 傻瓜 ?
What did you do, you great pudding?
我 沒 做什 么 !
I didn't do 'owt!
- 關上 ! - 關 不上 !
- Turn it off! - It won't turn off!
敦 蒂 太太 雞 肉 餡 餅
我們 應該 給 其他 人 看看
- Ouch! - We've got to show the others
瞧 ! 我 修 好了 !
Look! I fixed it!
雞 肉 餡 餅 ?
Chicken pies?
- 對 但 ... - 我 不想 成為 餡 餅 !
- Yes, but... - I don't want to be a pie!
我 不喜歡 調味 汁
I don't like gravy
女士 們 請 保持 頭腦 清醒
Ladies, please. Let's not lose our heads
頭腦 清醒 ?
Lose our heads?
我 是 說 洛 基 破壞 了 機器
What I meant was, Rocky sabotaged the machine
為 我們 贏得 了 時間
and bought us time
更 妙 的 是 明天 他 要 為 我們 飛行
And better still, he's going to fly for us tomorrow
一旦 我們 看到 了 示 范 我們 就 可以 飛 了 !
And once we've seen how it's done, we'll get it!
因此 別 擔心
So don't worry
因為 明天 一切
because tomorrow everything's
都 會 非常 順利
going to go much, much smoother
老 爺 爺 我 又 做錯 什 么 了 ?
All right, Pops, what did I do now?
非常 勇敢 光榮 的 行動 先生
A very brave and honorable deed, sir
從 今晚 你的 行動 來 看
In the light of your action this evening
我 鄭重 地 承認 我 錯 看了 你
I dutifully admit that I have misjudged your character
因此 我 為 你的 勇敢 頒 發 給 你 一 枚 獎 章
So I present you with this medal for bravery
并 且 ...
And...
向 你 致敬
I salute you
在 此 光榮 的 時刻
In honor of the occasion
我 讓 出 我 整個 床 鋪
I surrender the bunk entirely
我 去 外面 睡覺
I shall sleep under the stars.
啊 我 懷 著 極大 的 期望 ...
Oh, uh, I await tomorrow's flying demonstration...
等 著 待 明天 的 飛行 示 范
with great anticipation
我 也是 啊 老 爺 爺
You and me both, Pops
對不起 你 ...
- Oh! - I'm sorry. Were you...
這 是 你的 ... 我 走了
Is this your... I'll go.
不 只不過
No, it's just...
因為 你 在 這 兒 ...
Since you're here!
我 很 高興 因為 ...
I'm glad you're here, because...
對不起 你 先 說
I'm sorry. You go first.
你 先 說 我 ...
You go ahead. I'll...
我 只想 說 ...
Um, I just wanted to say...
我 當初 可能 有 點 兒 粗魯
I may have been a bit harsh at first
啊 我 真正 指 的 是
Well, what I really mean is
謝謝你 ...
thank you...
救 了 我 的 命
for saving my life
救 了 大家 的 命
For saving OUR lives
你 知道
You know
我 每 晚 到 這 兒 來 ...
I come up here every night!
來 看 那 座山 丘
and look out to that hill
想 象 著 山 那邊 的 生活
and imagine what it must be like on the other side
有 趣 的 是 我 ...
It's funny, I've...
從來 沒 感到 站 在 草原 上 的 感覺
I've never actually felt grass beneath my feet
對不起
I'm sorry
我 現在 在 山丘 和 草地 上 散步
Here I am rambling on about hills and grass
你 有 什 么 話 要說 嗎 ?
and you had something to say
是 這樣 你 知道
Um, it's just that, y- you know
那邊 兒 的 生活 以我 來 看
life, as I've experienced it, you know, out there
從 孤獨 自由 浪 人 的 經歷 來 看
lone free ranging and stuff, it's, uh
令人 失望
it's full of disappointments, and, uh...
什 么 你 是 說 草地 不像 傳說 的 那樣 好
What, you mean grass isn't all it's cracked up to be?
草地 ! 正是 草地
Grass! Exactly. Grass
另一邊 兒 的 草 總是 比較 綠
It's always greener on the other side
但 當 你 到 那 兒時 它 就 變得 枯萎 多 刺
And then you get there and it's brown and prickly
你 明白 我 想 表達 的 意思 嗎 ?
You see what I'm trying to say?
我 想說 的 是 ...
What I'm trying to say is...
別 客 氣
you're welcome
你 知道
You know
今晚 那 山丘
that hill is looking closer tonight
比 任何 時候 離 我 都 近
than it ever has before
哦 晚 安 ... 洛 基
Well, good night... Rocky
晚 安 ... 姜 妹
Good night... Ginger
各位 立 正 !
Company, attention!
姑娘 們 今天 就是 我們 飛行 的 日子 了
Today's the day, girls. We're going to fly!
我 感到 很 興奮 !
I can feel it!
終 于 可以 看到 真正 的 專家 飛行
Finally, we get to see a real professional in action
最好 開始 熱 身 我 去 叫 他 來
Better start warming up. I'll go and get him
洛 基 開門
Rocky. Knock- knock.
大家 在 等 你 我 告訴 他們 先 ...
Everyone's waiting, so I told them to...
洛 基 ?
R- Rocky?
啊 一 門 大 炮
Oh, a cannon
當然 這 可以 給 你 動 力
Aye, that would give you thrust
我 早就 知道 他 是 騙子
I knew he was fake all along
實際上 我 甚至 懷疑 他 是 美國 人
In fact, I'm not even certain he was American
那 下一步 該 怎 么 辦 各位 ?
So, what's the next plan, hen?
我們 面對 現實 吧
Let's face it
離開 這 兒 唯 一 的 方法 是 包 在 餡 餅 里
The only way out of here is wrapped in pastry
也許 他 只是 去 度 假 了
Perhaps he just went on holiday
也許 是 逃離
Perhaps he just went to get away
你 不停 的 編織 !
from your infernal knitting!
你 總是 打 他
You were always hitting him
換 了 你 會 怎樣 !
See how YOU like it!
不要 推 我 四 眼 !
Don't push me, four- eyes!
安靜 我 說 安靜 !
Quiet there! Quiet, I say!
內訌 正是
Dissension in the ranks.
敵人 想見 到 的
Precisely what Jerry would have wanted
分裂 后 再 征服 的 老 辦法
The old divide and conquer
像 我們 在 皇家 空 軍 那樣
A proper squadron work together
一個 中 隊 一起 工作
like we did in my R. A. F. days
卓 高 負責 駕駛 法 比 負責 導 航 ...
Jocko at the stick, Flappy at the map...
老 韋 茲 邦 負責 機 尾 機 槍
and old Whizzbang at the tail- end Charlie
長官 一 聲 令 下
Wing Co would give the call
跳進 飛 機 立刻 起 飛 !
hop in the old crate, chocks away!
魔 力 將 引導 你 獎 章 就是 這樣 獲得 的
Wizard show it was. That's how you get medals
你 能不能 閉 上 嘴
Will you shut up about
別 談 你 那 臭 獎 章 !
your stupid blooming medals!
你 怎 么 敢 這樣 !
How dare you!
女士 原諒 我 作為 一個 長官
Madam, forgive me. A- As an officer
我 要 ...
I offer my most...
福樂
Fowler?
各位 閉嘴 !
Everyone, shut up!
福樂
Fowler
皇家 空 軍 到底是 什 么 ?
What exactly is the R. A. F. ?
你 指 什 么 它是 什 么 ?
What do you mean, what is it?
就是 皇家 空 軍 部隊
The Royal Air Force is what.
" 老 飛 機 " 又是 什 么 ?
Then what's the " old crate" ?
就 在 那 兒
Ahh! There she is
真 漂亮 是 不是 ?
Gorgeous, isn't she?
你 是 說 你 坐 過 這個 ?
You mean, you flew in one of these?
做得 真 漂亮
Beautifully built.
實際上 還有 段 故事 呢
In fact, there's a bit of a story to that
我們 有 次 去 偵察 你 知道
We were out on a " recce, " you see
上 頭 說 前進
Ops had given the go- ahead
但 天氣 很 差
but the weather duffed up...
對 當然
Yes. Of course
我們 實際上 是 可以 成功 的
We might actually be able to pull this off
- 我們 還要 飛 ! - 什 么 什 么 ?
- We're STILL going to fly! - What, what?
福樂 提供 了 答案
Fowler's provided the answer
我 提供 了 ?
I have?
對 對 我 當然 提供 了
Uh, yes, yes, yes. Of course I have
我 怎 么 提供 的 ?
Uh, how have I?
我們 要 建造 ...
We'll make...
一個 老 飛 機
a crate
麥 克 你 負責 工程 技 術
Mac, you'll handle the engineering
巴 波斯 生產 制 造
Babs, manufacturing
范 樂 是 首席 飛行 顧問
Fowler will be chief aviation advisor
邦 迪 雞蛋
Bunty, eggs
- 雞蛋 ? - 雞蛋
- Eggs? - Eggs
對 就像 公 雞 要 下 的 蛋
Right, just like the ones that rooster was gonna lay
可是 公 雞 不下 蛋 是 不是 ?
Only roosters don't lay eggs, do they?
不下 ?
Don't they?
不下 那 無疑 是 母雞 的 活 兒
No, it's a lady thing, apparently
問 問你 媽
Ask your mum
單 子上 的 貨 一個 雞蛋 一件
One egg for every item on the list.
首 批 貨 先 交 蛋
First payment in advance
好 ! 我們 啥 時 開始 ?
Right! When do we start?
來 !
Come on!
到底是 什 么 ?
What the dickens?
啊 小 精 靈
Oh, gnomes now
在 這 兒 !
Voila!
給 我
Give me
來自 上天 的 蛋 !
Eggs from heaven!
不 ! 來自 她 屁股 的 蛋 !
No! From her bum!
- 白 癡 ! - 差 點 兒 修 好了
- Idiot! - That was close
差 一點點 兒
Too close
我們 不能 停下 來
We can't stop now. Come on
各位 我們 干 吧 !
everyone! Go for it!
真的 要 造了 ! 快 快
Really go for it! Go, go, go, go!
麥 克 我們 急 需 那些 計算 數字
Mac, we need those calculations quickly
安 吉 絲 那一 定要 結實
Agnes, that has to be really secure
- 福樂 你 要 小心 ! - 收 到
- Careful up there, Fowler! - Roger!
邦 迪 幫 他 一把
Bunty, give him a hand
干 得 好 巴 波斯 繼續 努力
Well done, Babs. Keep it up
沒 問題 娃 娃 臉
No problem, dollface
啊 我 是 那 種
Oh, I'm the type of guy
喜歡 旅 游 的 人
That likes to roam around
我 從不 呆 在 一個 地方
I'm never in one place
從 一個 城市 到 另一 個 城市
I roam from town to town
當 我 發現 愛 上 某個 姑娘 時
And when I found myself falling for some girl
我 就 跳進 那個 車 ...
I'd hop right in that car...
女人 的 手藝
And travel 'round the world
Cause I'm a wanderer
Yeah a wanderer
I roam around and round around and round...
新 貨 - 敦 蒂 太太 雞 肉 餡 餅
啊 天 啊
Oh, boy
快
Come on
快 開
Please
啊 不 他 修 好了
Oh, no. He's fixed it
去抓 雞 來
Get the chickens
哪一 只 ?
Which ones?
所有 的 雞
All of them
我 的 工具 !
Me tools!
啊 你們 這些 小偷 !
Why, you thieving little buggers!
怎 么 辦 呢 ?
What's the plan?
進攻 !
Attack!
好主意
Nice plan
敦 蒂 太太 !
Mrs. Tweedy!
Aaaah! Mrs. Tweedy!
雞 都 造反 了 !
The chickens are revolting!
惡 心 我們 的 看法 終 于 一致 了
Finally something we agree on
救命 ! 太太 ...
Help! Mrs... .
放 在 小 屋 下面
Under the hut
- 我們 做了 些 什 么 ? - 就 這樣 各位
- What have we done? - This is it, everyone
我們 逃跑
We're escaping
- 什 么 現在 ? - 現在 !
- What, now? - Now!
- 但是 飛 機 還沒 準備 好 - 聽 著
- But, Ginger, she's not ready. - Listen
我們 不是 做 自由 的 雞 就是 為 自由 而 死
We'll either die free chickens or die trying
只有 這 兩種 選擇 嗎 ?
Are those the only choices?
- 我們 開始 吧 ! - 緊急 行動 !
- Let's do it! - Scramble!
這 邊 兒 來 !
This way!
敦 蒂 太太 !
Mrs. Tweedy!
這 里 那 里 都 有 出口
The exits are located here and here
一旦 出現 緊急 情況
In the quite likely event of an emergency
把 腦袋 放 在 膝蓋 之間 ...
put your head between your knees and...
抱 著 屁股 說 聲 再見
Kiss your bum good- bye
好 福樂 準備 起 飛
All right, Fowler, ready for takeoff
一路 跟 在 你 后面
Behind you all the way
但 你 應該 在 上面
But you're supposed to be up there
你 是 飛行 員 啊
You're the pilot
別 開玩笑
Oh, don't be ridiculous.
我 不會 開這 個 怪物
I can't fly this contraption
想 當年 你 ... 在 皇家 空 軍 ...
Back in your day... The Royal Air Force...
6- 4- 4 中 隊 家禽 師
6- 4- 4 Squadron, poultry division
我們 是 吉祥 物
We were the mascots
你 是 說你 從來 沒 開 過 飛 機 ?
You mean you never actually flew the plane?
天 啊 沒有
Good heavens, no
我 是 只 雞 啊 !
I'm a chicken!
皇家 空 軍
The Royal Air Force doesn't
不讓 雞 駕駛
let chickens behind the controls
復 雜 的 飛 機 !
of a complex aircraft!
我們 都要 沒命 了 !
We're all gonna die!
福樂 你 必須 駕駛
Fowler, you have to fly it
你 總是 提 你 想 當年
You're always talking about back in your day.
好 今天 就 看 你的 了
Well, today is your day
你 能行 你 這個 老家 伙
You can do it, you old sausage
聯 隊 指揮 福樂 ...
Wing Commander T. I. Fowler...
奉命 報到
reporting for duty
好啊 來 你 還 在 等 什 么 ?
Well, come on. What are you waiting for?
我們 的 時間 不多 了
We haven't got all day.
我們 把 飛 機 飛 起來
Let's get this crate off the ground
福樂 ! 開始 !
Fowler! Now!
收 到 ! 目 測 !
Roger! Contact!
可以 起 飛 !
Cleared for takeoff!
從 這 兒 升天 起 飛
起 飛 了 !
Chocks away!
- 開 足 馬 力 ! - 開 足 馬 力 !
- Full throttle! - Full throttle!
我們 需要 更大 的 馬 力 !
We need more power!
我 不能 創造 奇 跡 隊長 !
I cannot work miracles, Cap'n!
我們 已經 開 足 了 馬 力
We're giving her all she's got
- 跑 不了 了 ! - 使勁 往 右 !
- Gotcha! - Hard right!
啊 媽 呀 !
Oh, mother!
掉過 頭 去 我 來把 板 放 好
Turn her around. I'll get the ramp
把 板子 放下
Put the ramp down.
你 就 要 成為 餡 餅 了 !
You are going to be a pie!
姜 妹 !
Ginger!
洛 基 !
Rocky!
抬起頭來 !
Heads up!
- 小心 ! - 離開 跑 道 !
- Look out! - Clear the runway!
姜 妹 ! 我們 走 !
Ginger! Let's go!
我們 在 飛 !
We're flying!
這 是 為 逃走
That's for leaving
這 是 為 回來
And this is for coming back
天 啊 ! 那是 什 么 ?
Great Scott! What was that?
是 附 屬 物 機 長
A cling- on, Cap'n
引 擎 吃 不消 了 !
and the engines can't take it!
啊 天 啊
Oh, goodness
巴 波斯 ! 剪刀 !
Babs! Scissors!
找到 了
Bingo
把 我 放下
Lower me down
- 可是 姜 妹 我 ... - 就 這 么 做
- But, Ginger, I... - Just do it
加 快速 度 !
Increase velocity!
什 么 意思 ?
What does that mean?
踩到 你們 斷氣 為止 !
Pedal your flipping giblets out!
- 低 點 兒 ! - 知道了 !
- Lower! - I'm trying!
福樂 當心 !
Fowler, look out!
姜 妹 !
Oh! Ginger!
開 火 ! 開 火 !
Fire! Fire!
我 的 雞蛋
Me eggs.
不 !
No!
加 彈 藥 ! 快 !
More ammo! Hurry!
- 雞蛋 沒有 了 ! - 姜 妹 ! 當心 !
- We got no more eggs! - Ginger! Look out!
不 !
No!
再見
Bye- bye
投 彈 完畢 !
Bombs away!
敦 蒂 太太 !
Mr. Tweedy!
啊 這 太好了 太好了 !
Oh, that was good. That was good!
老家 伙 完 蛋 了 !
The old bird bought it!
敦 蒂 太太 ! 敦 蒂 太太 ...
Mrs. Tweedy! Mrs. Twee...
安全 閥 門 保持 暢 通
危險
我 告訴 過 你 他們 是有 組織 的
I told you they was organized
我們 成功 了 各位 !
We did it, everyone!
繼續 踩 ! 我們 還沒 完全 成功 !
Keep pedaling! We're not there yet!
別 松 勁 不然就 到 不了 天 堂 了
You can't see paradise if you don't pedal!
再 加 把 勁 !
Put your drumsticks into it!
這 就是 我 告訴 他的 如此 這 般
That's what I told him. What, what
我們 正在 失去 高度
We were losing altitude
你 看 就 要 一 頭 栽 地 了
you see, and heading for a fearful prang
這 是 一個 愉快 的 假 日
This is a lovely holiday
回去 我 會 傷心 的
I'll be sad to go back
安全 永遠 第一
Safety at all times is imperative
現在 把 線 拉緊 再 ...
Now, wind 'er up and...
放手
Let 'er go!
這 ... 跟 你 想 象 的 一樣 嗎 ?
So... is it as good as you imagined?
不 一樣
No.
更好
It's better.
來 我 教 你 打 板 球
Come on. I'll show you how to play cricket
我 有 個問題
Here's a thought
為 什 么 我們 不 拿個 雞蛋 自己 開 一個 養 雞 場
Why don't we get an egg and start our own chicken farm?
這樣 我們 就 有 吃 不 完 的 雞蛋
That way we'll have all the eggs we could eat
對 那 么 我們 需要 一 只 雞
Right. We'll need a chicken, then
不 不 我們 需要 一 只 蛋
No. No, we'll need an egg
你 要 先有 蛋
You have the egg first.
然 后 才有 雞
That's where you get the chicken from
雞 之 圣 殿 一 閑 人 免 進
不 沒有 雞
No, that's cobblers. Without a chicken
哪 來 的 蛋
where you gonna get an egg?
哪 來 生 蛋 的 雞
From the chicken that comes from the egg
對 但 你 得 先有 蛋 才能 有 雞
Yeah, but you have to have an egg to have a chicken
但是 沒有 雞 哪 來 的 蛋
But you gotta get the chicken first to get the egg
哪 來 的 蛋 孵 小雞
and then the egg to get the chicken out of
等等 我們 再 重 來 一遍
Hang on. Let's go over this again
劇 終
Yeow
All right
Oh yeah
When I get the blues gon'get me a rocking chair
When the blues overtake me
Gonna rock on away from here ohh
Here comes my baby flashing a new gold tooth
Yeah she's so small
She can rumba in a pay phone booth
That's the truth ha- ha!
Flip flop fly
I don't care if I die
Don't ever leave me don't ever say good- bye
Yeow!
Now give me one more kiss
And hold it a long long time
Give me one more kiss
Love me baby till the feeling hits my head like wine
So fine so glad that you're mine
Flip flop fly
I don't care if I die
Don't ever leave me don't ever say good- bye
Bye- bye bye- bye
Yeah!
Bye- bye!
雞蛋 很 顯然
The egg, obviously
很 高興 地 滾 動 著
Rolling along, happy as Larry
后 來 喀 嚓 ! 孵 出了 第一 只 雞
Then, crack! Hatches into the first chicken
對 可是 這 蛋 是 從 哪兒 來 的 ?
Yeah, but where'd the egg come from, then?
你 是 什 么 意思 從 哪兒 來 ?
What do you mean, where'd it come from?
雞蛋 高興 地 從 地上 滾來
Egg comes rolling along, happy as Larry
它 在 想 它是 從 哪兒 來 的 ?
It's wondering where'dit come from?
沒有 雞 就 沒有 滾 動 的 蛋
Without a chicken, you get no egg to come rolling along
同樣 沒有 孵 小雞 的 蛋
Well, conversely, without an egg to hatch into the chicken
就 沒有 下蛋 的 雞
there will be no chicken to lay the other egg
沒有 下蛋 的 雞
that hatches into the chicken
哪 來 的 蛋 來 孵 小雞
that lays the egg I mentioned first
- 我們 現在 有 兩 只 蛋 了 ? - 沒有
- We got two eggs now? - No
我們 仍 在 討論 最 早 的 那 只 蛋
We're still talking about the very first egg
最 早 的 那 只 雞 呢 ?
What about the very first chicken?
它 在 最 早 的 那 只 蛋 里 !
He's in the very first egg!
- 你 在 聽 嗎 ? - 伙 計 伙 計 ?
- Aren't you listening? - Uh, guys. Guys?
努力 享受 這 里 的 天 堂 生活
Trying to enjoy paradise over here
- 啊 對不起 朋友 - 再說 一遍
- Oh, sorry, guv. - Beg your pardon
- 再也 不會 這樣 了 - 謝謝
- Won't happen again. - Thanks
- 笨 蛋 - 混 蛋
- Gitface. - Pillock
以為 他 上了 海 報
Thinks he's such a big shot 'cause
就 了 不起
he's got his name on a poster
這些 藝人 都是 這樣
These show biz folk are all the same
- 老鼠 是 明星 - 是 當然是
- The rats are the stars. - Yeah, of course they are
我們 出 力 他 出名
We do all the 'ard work, he gets all the credit
- 他 得到 了 一切 - 對 他 得到 了 一切
- He gets everything. - Yes, he does. Everything